BRIAN HOANG

Front End Web Developer

INFO

Phone: 07852786300

Email: bhoang35@gmail.com

Website: https://brian-hoang.com

KEY SKILLS

- Intuitive Design
- Code Optimization
- UI Enhancement
- Security Minded Development
- Project Management
- Issue Resolution

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Development

- HTML5
- SASS
- CSS3 (Bootstrap, Material UI)
- JavaScript (ES6, TypeScript)
- iQuery
- React (Redux, Gatsby, Router)

Back-End Development

- PHP
- Node.js (Express)
- PostgreSQL
- Redis
- AWS (Lambda, EC2, S3)

Other

- Webpack
- Jest (Enzyme)
- Git (GitHub, Heroku)
- Photoshop
- Premiere
- After Effects

PROFILE

Self-taught Web Developer with the ability to conceptualize and deliver responsive, user-friendly solutions effectively and efficiently. Helped curate the online experience of several businesses to gain and retain customers by creating appealing and informative content. Continue to improve skills individually as well as communally through meetups and hackathons.

EXPERIENCE

BAMM London (April 2018) – Edited and translated several interviews for Shell regarding their products and brand in Vietnam, constructing a better understanding of the people and the market for the client.

MDC Gifts (August 2016 - Present) – Managing ecommerce and graphic design as well as posting and creating content for social media on Facebook, Instagram and Twitter, increasing customer engagement and satisfaction in the brand.

Barr Pictures (August 2015 - Present) – Editing documentaries for a myriad of organisations that have to meet varying needs and goals, which have been showcased and aired across the globe.

Fiorella Shoes (February 2015 - Present) – Overseeing online business on ecommerce platforms as well as graphic design for their website and products that has helped drive up traffic on product pages and increase sales.

EDUCATION

GOLDSMITH'S UNIVERSITY OF LONDON (2011 -2014)

BA Media and Communications (Second Class Honours Upper Division)

Key Achievement: Developed a film from the ground up, not only on the production side, but also using keen managerial and organisation skills to assist with logistics, financing and promotion.